Our words are stronger than their weapons.
City of Ghosts is a war, documentary film directed by Matthew Heineman.
With unprecedented access, this documentary follows the extraordinary journey of “Raqqa is Being Slaughtered Silently”—a group of anonymous citizen journalists who
banded together after their homeland was overtaken by ISIS—as they risk their lives to stand up against one of the greatest evils in the world today.
Self, played by Abu Bakr Al-Baghdadi.
Self, played by Hamoud.
Hamoud's brother, played by Hassan.
Self, played by Hussam.
Self, played by Naji Jerf.
Self, played by Mohamad.
City of Ghosts (Arabic: مدينة الأشباح, romanized: Madīnat al-Ashbāḥ) is a 2017 Arabic-language American documentary film about the Syrian media activist group Raqqa Is
Being Slaughtered Silently as they face the realities of life undercover, on the run, and in exile after their homeland is taken over by ISIS in 2014.
The film was directed by Oscar-nominated and Emmy
Award-winning filmmaker Matthew Heineman (Cartel Land).
Heineman won the Outstanding Directorial Achievement in Documentary Award from the Directors Guild of
America for the film, becoming one of only three people to win the prestigious honor twice.
City of Ghosts also won the Courage Under Fire Award from the International Documentary Association "in recognition of conspicuous
bravery in the pursuit of truth" and was listed on over 20 critic and year-end lists for Best Documentary of 2017.
City of Ghosts was nominated for the Primetime Emmy Award for Exceptional Merit in Documentary
Filmmaking, BAFTA Award, PGA Award, IDA Award for Best Documentary Features.